<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  
<!ENTITY rcversion "2.0">
<!ENTITY manversion "2.0">
<!ENTITY pubdate "March, 2003">

]>

<article id="index" lang="en">
 <articleinfo>
    <title>Ximian Red Carpet</title>
    <copyright>
      <year>2000-2003</year>
      <holder>Ximian Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>    
    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">     
      <para>
        Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
        document under the terms of the <ulink type="help"
        url="gnome-help:fdl"><citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
        License</citetitle></ulink>, Version 1.1 or any later version
        published by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant
        Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. You
        may obtain a copy of the <citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
        License</citetitle> from the Free Software Foundation by
        visiting <ulink type="http" url="http://www.fsf.org">their Web
        site</ulink> or by writing to: Free Software Foundation, Inc.,
        59 Temple Place - Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.
      </para>
      <para>
        Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their
        products and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those
        names appear in any GNOME documentation, and those trademarks
        are made aware to the members of the GNOME Documentation
        Project, the names have been printed in caps or initial caps.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
    <releaseinfo>
       This is version &manversion; of the guide to Ximian Red Carpet, describing Ximian Red
       Carpet &rcversion;. It was last updated &pubdate;.
    </releaseinfo>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>
       <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application> is a program designed to
       help you manage the software you have on your computer. It can
       help you install, update, and remove programs, without making you keep
       track of dependencies and conflicts yourself.  It works with
       the package management structures your operating systems
       already has, so you can use it alongside unrelated command-line
       tools.
    </para>
    
    <para>
      Red Carpet 2 has a number of important differences from the
      previous version.  The appearance and interface have been
      completely overhauled, and there are several new features like
      enhanced search tools and the ability to make a list of removals
      and installations, then then do everything at once.
    </para>

    <para>
      One important structural difference is that, as of version
      2.0, Red Carpet the graphical tool is actually a client for
      <application>rcd</application>, the Red Carpet Daemon.
      Having two pieces means:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can update remote systems that are running the
            daemon. Select
            <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Connect</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
            to choose a remote host.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            You have a choice between the graphical
            <systemitem>red-carpet</systemitem> program and the
            command line <systemitem>rc</systemitem> tools. Both tools
            require the <systemitem>rcd</systemitem> package.   Detailed information about
            <application>rc</application> and <application>rcd</application>
            are available in their man pages (standard UNIX manuals). You
            can read them by typing <userinput>man rc</userinput> or
            <userinput>man rcd</userinput> at the command line. 
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>


    <note id="whats-a-package">
      <title>What is a Package?</title>
      <para>
        Software for most versions of Linux is shipped as a
        <emphasis>package</emphasis> file, most commonly the 
        <systemitem>rpm</systemitem> or <systemitem>deb</systemitem>
        format. Each package contains a set of files that constitute
        the software itself, plus additional information about what
        the software is, what requirements it has, and where it should
        be installed.  Proper packaging makes software easier to
        install, upgrade, or remove, and can help manage the
        interdependencies among various programs.
      </para>
      <para>
        Ximian Red Carpet supports the <systemitem>rpm</systemitem>
        (Red Hat Package Manager, used by most distributions), and the
        <systemitem>deb</systemitem> (Debian) package formats.
      </para>
    </note>


    <note id="whats-a-channel">
      <title>What are Channels and Sections?</title>
      <para>
        Ximian Red Carpet groups software into channels.  For example,
        "Red Hat 8.0," "Ximian Evolution Beta Snapshots,"
        and "Ximian Desktop" are all channels.  You can subscribe to
        channels that interest you, and ignore those that do
        not. Ximian Red Carpet will not install or update software
        from channels to which you are not installed.
      </para>
   
      <para>
        To subscribe to a channel, select    <menuchoice>
        <guimenu>Edit</guimenu><guimenuitem>Channel Subscriptions</guimenuitem>
        </menuchoice> or press the <guibutton>Channels</guibutton> button
        in the toolbar. A window will open to show you the list of
        available channels. Check the box next to a channel to subscribe.
      </para>

      <para>
        Some channels also have groupings called sections, which
        describe the purpose of the individual pieces of
        software. "Imaging," "Productivity," and "Development" are
        examples of sections.
      </para>
    </note>

    <para>
      Ximian Red Carpet also gives you access to two important
      services from Ximian, Inc.  The first service, Red Carpet
      Express, is for individuals, and offers
      access to special high-speed servers with faster connections,
      so you get better download rates.  The other service, Ximian Red
      Carpet Enterprise, is aimed at businesses and workgroups that
      want to manage software deployment on a larger scale.
    </para>

    <para>
      To find out more about using Red Carpet Express, read <xref
      linkend="rcx" />.  For more about Red Carpet Enterprise
      visit the <ulink
      url="http://ximian.com/products/red_carpet_enterprise">Ximian
      website</ulink>.
    </para>

    <note id="note-requirements">
      <title>Software Requirements</title>
      <para>
         <itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
            Ximian update and installation services require a network
              connection. If you do not have a network connection, you
              can still use Ximian Red Carpet to remove software or
              install local packages that you already have on disk. To
              install from a file, select
              <menuchoice> <guimenu>File</guimenu> <guimenuitem>Install
              Local Packages</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice>. For information on removing software, see
          <xref linkend="rc-my-computer" />.
          </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para>
             To install, update, or remove software, you must enter
             your system's root password.  If you do not have root
             privileges, you may only view the software installed on
             your system.
          </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              Ximian ships software for a limited number of operating
              systems. Not all software is available for all systems.
              The official list of supported systems is available at
              the <ulink url="http://support.ximian.com/q?5">Ximian
              Support Center</ulink>.
            </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
     </note>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="getting-started">
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <para>
      To start using <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application>, select
      <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>System</guimenu><guimenuitem>Software
      Update</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the menu panel, or type
      <userinput>red-carpet</userinput> at the command line. Enter
      your root password when prompted.
    </para>

    <para>
      The Red Carpet window has two major sections that display
      information.  In the center, there is a list of software
      packages.  On the left side of the window is a list of
      transactions.  As you use Red Carpet, you will choose software
      from the package list to install or remove, adding the
      installation or removal to the list of actions.
    </para>
      <para>
        For detailed information about a package, select it and click
        the <guibutton>Information</guibutton> button.
      </para>

      <tip id="sort-order">
        <title>Sort Order</title>
        <para>
          To change the way information is sorted, click the headers
          at the top of the columns of data. For example, to sort
          software in alphabetical order by package name, click
          the <guilabel>Package</guilabel> header. Click again to sort
          in reverse alphabetical order.
        </para>
      </tip>

     <para>
       To select a package, click on it with the left mouse button. You
       can select multiple packages by holding down
       <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> and clicking, or select a range using
       <keycap>Shift</keycap>. To select all packages in the list,
       press <keycombo><keycap>Ctrl</keycap><keycap>A</keycap></keycombo>.
     </para>

    <para>
      To mark a package for installation or removal, click the
      <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> or <guibutton>Mark
      for Removal</guibutton> buttons at the bottom of the screen.
    </para>

    <note id="transaction-types">
      <title>How Many Kinds of Transactions Are There?</title>
      <para>
        There are only two basic kinds of transactions in Red
        Carpet: installation and removal.  An upgrade is essentially
        the removal of the old version and installation of the new
        one. Therefore, there are only two actions you can choose:
        <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> and <guibutton>Mark for
        Removal.</guibutton>
      </para>
      <para>
        Where appropriate, Red Carpet displays upgrades as though
        they were single transactions. For example, the 
        <guilabel>History</guilabel> view has an
        <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column that displays upgrades as
        well as installs or removals.
      </para>
    </note>

    <para>
      To remove an item from the list of pending transactions, select
      it and click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> or right-click on it and
      select <guimenuitem>Cancel</guimenuitem>.
    </para>

    <para>
      When you are done choosing actions, click the <guibutton>Run
      Now</guibutton> button. Red Carpet will then check to see if
      additional actions are required. For example, if you attempt to
      install a new spelling dictionary, but do not have the spelling
      tool, you will need to install the the spelling tool as well as
      the dictionary.
    </para>
    <para>
       Red Carpet will present you with a list of the actions that it
       is about to take, and ask you to confirm or cancel. If you are
       satisfied with the set of actions, click
       <guibutton>Continue</guibutton>.
    </para>
    <tip id="tip-mirrors">
      <title>Use a Mirror for Faster Downloads</title>
      <para>
        For best performance, select a mirror near you. To learn how
        to choose a mirror, and why mirrors can give you a faster
        download, read <xref linkend="prefs-general" />.
      </para>
    </tip>

  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="five-views">
    <title>Five Ways of Looking at Software</title>
   
    <para>
      At the top left of the Ximian Red Carpet window are five buttons
      that display five different views of the software world: 
    </para>
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Updates</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This is the view you will see when you start Ximian Red
              Carpet. It displays updates to software that you have
              installed and that is in channels to which you are subscribed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>My Computer</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This displays software that is installed on your
              computer.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Search</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This lets you search the largest possible list of
              packages: those installed on your system, and those
              available for installation in all channels.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>History</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This displays a list of actions you have performed in
              the past.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Pending Actions</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This displays the upcoming software transactions you
              have chosen. To perform them, click the <guibutton>Run
              Now</guibutton> button.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <sect2 id="rc-update">
        <title>Perform Updates</title>
        <para>
          When you start Ximian Red Carpet it will show you a list of
          software packages that you can update. An update notice is only
          shown for software that you already have installed, that is in a
          channel to which you are subscribed, and for which there is a
          newer version than what you already have. New software, and new
          versions of software that you have but that is in a channel to
          which you do not subscribe, is not part of the update screen.
        </para>

        <para>
          If you do not see any updates, make sure that you are subscribed
          to the right channels. See <xref linkend="whats-a-channel" /> to learn
          how to adjust channel subscriptions.
        </para>


      <para>
        Each package is displayed with the following information:
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing for this package. This
                entry will be blank if you are neither installing nor
                removing it.  If you have selected an action, it will
                have an installation or removal icon. You can click on
                the blank space to perform an action (install a package
                if it is not installed, remove a package if it is
                installed), or click on the icon to cancel the action.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Importance</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Ximian will indicate how important it is for you to
                install this update. From least to most important,
                an update can be listed as minor, feature, suggested,
                urgent, or necessary.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Channel</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the channel in which this package is
                shipped. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>New Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number for the updated package. Note that
                version numbers do not count by digits, but instead
                use numbers separated by. In other words, version 1.10
                is newer than version 1.9. You can remember this by
                referring to "one point ten" instead of "one point one
                zero."
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the software you have installed now.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
         </para>
   
        <para>
          To perform a simple update of software that is already on your system:
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select one or more packages in the list of available updates.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Mark the selected packages for installation by clicking the
                <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> button.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click the <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button to have Ximian
                Red Carpet perform the updates.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </para>
    </sect2>


      <sect2 id="rc-my-computer">
        <title>Remove Software on My Computer</title>
        <para>
          To uninstall software that is on your computer now, click
          the <guilabel>My Computer</guilabel> button. Red Carpet will
          display a list of the software that is on your system now.
        </para>
        <para>
          Each package is displayed with the following information:
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing on this package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
                    
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Channel</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the channel in which this package is
                shipped. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
               The name of the package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the software you have installed now.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    
        <para>
          There are three ways to change the items in the list:
        </para>
    
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Channel</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Choose from the list of channels to show only the software
                that comes from a particular channel.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Section</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Choose from the list of software sections to show only the
                software of that type. Some channels do not use section
                divisions.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Text Search</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                You can also search for a word or word fragment in the
                packages and their descriptions by typing into the text
                box above the list of packages.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <para>
          For this view and for the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> view, you
          will have the following additional search options:
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Search Package Descriptions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Check this box to search in package descriptions
                as well as package names.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>


          <varlistentry>
            <term>Any Words or All Words</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select <guilabel>Any Word</guilabel> for a broad
                search that matches any of the words you enter in
              the text box, or <guilabel>All Words</guilabel> to
              find only matches that contain all the words you enter.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Substrings or Whole Words</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select <guilabel>Substrings</guilabel> to search
              for word fragments, or <guilabel>Whole
              Words</guilabel> to search for whole words
              only. Package names are rarely whole words, so this
              is mostly useful for package descriptions.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>
      <sect2 id="rc-search">
          <title>Search for Software</title>
          <para>
            To look at the broadest possible range of software, and to
            find new software to install, click the <guibutton>Search</guibutton>
            button. This will <emphasis>not</emphasis> immediately display a list of all
            available software.  You must first search for the software
            you want to see. If you really wish to see every available
            piece of software, enter a blank search in the search
            box.
          </para>

          <para>
            To search for software, select one or more criteria for your
            search. You can choose:
          </para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Channel</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Narrow your search to a specific channel. If you do not
                  select anything, you will search in all channels to
                  which you are subscribed.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Section</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  The type of software you are looking for, such as
                  <guilabel>Productivity</guilabel> or
                  <guilabel>Imaging</guilabel>.The default is to search in
                  all sections.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Status</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  You can search for packages that are not installed,
                  packages that are installed, packages that you have
                  installed but for which a newer version is available, or
                  for packages of any status. The default is to search for
                  packages which you do not have installed.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Text Search</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Enter words or word fragments to search for, and
                  press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist> 
      <para>
        The advanced search options are the same as in <guilabel>My
        Computer</guilabel>. See <xref linkend="rc-my-computer" /> for
        more information.
      </para>


      <para>
        In the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> view, each package is
        displayed with the following information:
    </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing on this package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Status</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Indicates whether you have the software installed and
                if so, whether an update is available. If you do not
                have the software, the value is listed as <guilabel>not
                installed</guilabel>.  If you have the same version of
              the software as the one listed, the status will be 
                <guilabel>installed</guilabel>. If you have a
                different version, the listed package will be
                described as <guilabel>older</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>newer</guilabel> than the installed version.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Channel</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the channel in which this package is
                shipped. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lock Icon</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The column with the lock icon indicates whether the
                package is cryptographically signed.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the software package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>
    <sect2 id="rc-history">
      <title>View Past Transactions with History</title>
      <para>
        The history view displays a list of of your past
        transactions. That is, each time you install, remove, or
        upgrade a piece of software, it's recorded here.
      </para>

      <para>
        The history information is taken from the logs of the Red
        Carpet Daemon, <command>rcd</command>. It includes
        transactions made with the <command>rc</command> command line
      tool, but not changes made with <command>dpkg</command>,
        <command>apt-get</command>, or <command>rpm</command>.
      </para>

      <para>
        It displays the following information about each transaction:
      </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Time</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The time and date when the transaction occurred.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Whether you upgraded, installed, or removed the software.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>


          <varlistentry>
            <term>User</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The user who performed the action. In most cases, this
                will be <guilabel>root</guilabel>, but you may allow
                other users to use Red Carpet.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the software package involved in the transaction.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Old Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                For upgrades and removals, this is the version of the
                software you had installed before the transaction. For
                installs, this entry is blank.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>New Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                For Installs and Upgrades, this displays the version of the software after the transactions.
                For removals, this entry is blank.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      <para>
        To change the displayed list, you can choose one or more of
        the following criteria:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Transaction Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Normally, the <guilabel>History</guilabel> view shows
                you all transactions. You may choose instead to display just 
                installations,  removals, or  upgrades.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>User</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                 Normally, Red Carpet will show you transactions
                performed by all permitted users. If you have allowed
                other users to use Red Carpet, you may choose to
                display just their actions. If you have not allowed
                any other users to change the system, the only option
                here will be <guilabel>All</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date Range</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Normally, Red Carpet will show you the transactions in the last
                thirty days. You can choose a longer or shorter time frame if you wish..
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rc-transaction-view">
      <title>The Detailed Transaction View</title>
      <para>
        The left side of the main Red Carpet window shows you
        a list of transactions you have selected, but it doesn't have
        room to give you a lot of detail. For more information about
        your pending transaction list, click the
        <guibutton>Pending Actions</guibutton> button.
      </para>
      <para>
        In addition to the action and package name available in the
        concise view, the detailed transaction view lets you see see
        the package version number and the amount of disk space taken
        up by the package.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>


  <sect1 id="rcx">
    <title>Red Carpet Express: More Software, Faster</title>
    <para>
       Red Carpet Express is a premium service that
       provides you with exclusive access to high speed download
       servers, plus additional software not available through the free
       service. Red Carpet Express works like basic regular Red Carpet
      service, except there are more channels of software available,
      and you connect to a dedicated high-bandwidth server. A one-year
       subscription is included with the purchase of Ximian Desktop. 
    </para>
    <para>
      When you purchase a subscription, you will be given an
      activation key, which is a string of numbers and letters like
      <userinput>83ab2f90e821f000</userinput>. To activate your
      subscription, select <menuchoice> <guimenu>File</guimenu>
      <guimenuitem>Activate</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. A dialog will
      open and ask for your email address and the activation code.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can turn Red Carpet Express and other premium services on or
      off by selecting  <menuchoice> <guimenu>Edit</guimenu>
      <guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem> </menuchoice> and, under
      the <guilabel>General</guilabel> section, clicking the
      <guilabel>Enable Premium Services</guilabel> checkbox.
    </para>
    <para>
      To sign up for Red Carpet Express, or find more information about
      its benefits, visit <ulink
      url="http://store.ximian.com">http://store.ximian.com</ulink>. 
    </para>

    <note id="rce">
      <title>Red Carpet Enterprise</title>
      <para>
        Red Carpet Enterprise allows you to run your own Ximian Red
        Carpet server and distribute software to your network in a
        secure and convenient manner. Clients may connect with either Red
        Carpet or the "rc" command line tool, simplifying automated
        updates. The server includes a web interface and scriptable
        command line tools.  You can use Red Carpet Enterprise to
        manage installs and updates for internal or purchased software, plus
        easy redistribution of software from Ximian, SuSE YaST, and the Red
        Hat Network. For additional information, visit <ulink
        url="http://ximian.com">http://ximian.com</ulink>. 
      </para>
    </note>

  </sect1>
 

  <sect1 id="preferences">
    <title>Ximian Red Carpet Preferences</title>
    <para>
      To open the preferences window, select <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> <guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
      </menuchoice>. The window has four tabbed pages: General, Cache,
      Daemon, and Advanced.
    </para>
    <sect2 id="prefs-general">
      <title>General Preferences</title>
      <para>
         You can set the following preferences here:
         <variablelist>
           <varlistentry>
             <term>Server URL</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                 The location of the Red Carpet server you are
                   using. If you know the exact URL of a server, you can enter it here,
                   or choose one from the list of mirrors by clicking
                   the <guibutton>Mirrors</guibutton> button.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

               <varlistentry>
                 <term>Mirrors</term>
                 <listitem>
                   <para>
                     Click this button to get a list of mirrors you
                     can choose from. All of these servers have the
                     same software as the main Ximian server, and
                     update at least once per day. 
                   </para>
                   <para>
                     For best results, choose a mirror with a physical
                     location near yours.  That generally means that
                     there are fewer intermediate connections between
                     the server and your computer.  In addition, the
                     primary Ximian site is often crowded, so even a
                     relatively distant mirror can be faster. Another
                     way to get a faster connection is with Red Carpet
                     Express. See <xref linkend="rcx" /> for more information.
                   </para>
                 </listitem>
               </varlistentry>



             <varlistentry>
               <term>Enable Premium Services</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If you have already activated Red Carpet Express or
                   Red Carpet Enterprise services, you can turn them on and off here.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Require Package Signatures</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Ximian ships software with a cryptographic
                   signature. Unless you absolutely trust your server
                   (for example, you are using Red Carpet Enterprise)
                   you should leave this setting on for security.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Maximum number of packages to download at once</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If possible, Ximian Red Carpet will download
                   several packages at once in order to make the best
                   use of your network connection. If you have a very
                   fast connection, you may wish to increase this
                   number. If you are sharing your connection with
                   others, you may wish to reduce it.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>


             <varlistentry>
               <term>Use a Proxy</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If your network uses an HTTP proxy, check this box,
                   then enter the proxy URL. If necessary, also enter
                   your username and password. Because Ximian Red
                   Carpet does not depend on a particular desktop,
                   this setting must be entered independently of
                   the GNOME desktop proxy setting.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
           </variablelist>
         </para>
       </sect2>
       <sect2 id="rc-prefs-cache">
         <title>Download Cache Preferences</title>
         <para>
           Ximian Red Carpet stores downloaded files so that if you
           quit or cancel an operation, you can resume it quickly
           without downloading again. The <guilabel>Cache</guilabel>
           tab in the Preferences window lets you change cache handling
           behavior. Your options are:
           <variablelist>
             <varlistentry>
               <term>Cache downloaded packages and metadata</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If you don't want to cache anything, uncheck this box. It is normally on.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Location of cached data</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Enter the location where you will save cached files.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Cache Expiration</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   You can the cache to empty after a certain number
                   of days, or if its contents take up more than a certain amount of
                   space. By default, this happens after 30 days or
                   300 MB. If you turn off cache expiration, packages
                   will be kept until you delete them yourself by
                   clicking the <guibutton>Empty Cache</guibutton> button.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
           </variablelist>
         </para>
         <para>
           At the bottom of the window, you can empty the package
           cache by clicking the <guibutton>Empty Cache</guibutton>
           button.
         </para>
         </sect2>
         <sect2 id="rc-prefs-advanced">
           <title>Advanced Red Carpet Preferences</title>
           <para>
             The options available in this section are:
           </para>
           <variablelist>
       
             <varlistentry>
               <term>Dispatcher host</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   The dispatcher, or "magic" proxy, is used only in
                   complex Red Carpet Enterprise deployments. If you
                   are using one, your system administrator will give
                   you a hostname to enter here.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>


             <varlistentry>
               <term>Repackage for rollback</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                    When you upgrade or remove software, Ximian Red
                   Carpet normally just deletes the old
                   version. However, it is possible to "repackage" it,
                   creating an archived version so you can switch back 
                   if necessary.  Repackaging is time consuming and
                   uses significant amounts of disk space.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>


             <varlistentry>
               <term>Verify server SSL certificates with external authority</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   This setting demands that the Red Carpet server
                   have an identity certificate which is verified by
                   external authority organizations. An external
                   certificate is expensive and most servers will not
                   have one.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Use HTTP/1.0 for server communication</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Check this box if your proxy or server insists on
                   strict HTTP/1.0 protocol for communications.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term></term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Logging level for rcd-messages</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Operation messages are saved to the file
                   <filename>/var/log/rcd/rcd-messages</filename>
                   depending upon the degree of importance assigned to
                   them by the developer. A value of 1 will send
                   only the messages that are flagged as most important; 
                   6 will send every message, and 0 will send no messages.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Logging level for syslog</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Determines the amount of information sent to the
                   central operating system log. Messages are sent 
                   depending upon the degree of importance assigned to
                   them by the developer. A value of 1 will send only
                   the messages that are flagged as most important;
                   6 will send every message, and 0 will send no
                   messages.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
           </variablelist>

             <para>
               If you require finer control over the operation
               of Ximian Red Carpet, you may wish to edit the
               configuration files, as described in the man pages for
               <command>rc</command>, <command>rcd</command>, and
               <command>rcd.conf</command>.
             </para>
           </sect2>
         </sect1>
         
  <sect1 id="remote">
    <title>Using Red Carpet with Remote Systems</title>
    <para>
      Ximian Red Carpet may be used with remote systems running the
      Red Carpet Daemon, <command>rcd</command>.  You will need to
      have an account with the daemon on the remote system.
    </para>
    <para>
      To add an rcd account on the remote system, you must log in to that
      system as root, and use the <command>rc user-add -U username -P
      password</command> command. Then, you may administer the system
    without logging in as root.
    </para>
    <para>
      To connect to a remote system, do the following:
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Connect</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the <guibutton>Connect to a remote daemon</guibutton> button.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter the hostname and, if necessary, port for connection to the remote system.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter your user name and password.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the <guibutton>Connect</guibutton> button.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      Once you are connected you can view and administer the system as
      you would a local one, in accordance with the privileges granted
      to your account.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also use the <command>rc</command> command to administer
      a remote system. For information on the command line Red Carpet
      tools, use the <command>man rc</command> command.
    </para>
  </sect1>

</article>