<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  
<!ENTITY rcversion "2.0">
<!ENTITY manversion "2.0">
<!ENTITY pubdate "March, 2003">

]>

<article id="index" lang="en">
 <articleinfo>
    <title>Ximian Red Carpet</title>
    <copyright>
      <year>2000-2003</year>
      <holder>Ximian Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>    
    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">     
      <para>
        Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
        document under the terms of the <ulink type="help"
        url="gnome-help:fdl"><citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
        License</citetitle></ulink>, Version 1.1 or any later version
        published by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant
        Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts. You
        may obtain a copy of the <citetitle>GNU Free Documentation
        License</citetitle> from the Free Software Foundation by
        visiting <ulink type="http" url="http://www.fsf.org">their Web
        site</ulink> or by writing to: Free Software Foundation, Inc.,
        59 Temple Place - Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.
      </para>
      <para>
        Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their
        products and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those
        names appear in any GNOME documentation, and those trademarks
        are made aware to the members of the GNOME Documentation
        Project, the names have been printed in caps or initial caps.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
    <releaseinfo>
       This is version &manversion; of the guide to Ximian Red Carpet, describing Ximian Red
       Carpet &rcversion;. It was last updated &pubdate;.
    </releaseinfo>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="rc-intro">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
       <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application> is a program designed to
       help you manage the software you have on your computer. It can
       help you install, update, and remove programs, without making you keep
       track of dependencies and conflicts yourself.  It works with
       the package management structures your operating systems
       already has, so you can use it alongside command-line tools
       without running into conflicts.
    </para>
    
    <note id="whats-a-package">
      <title>What is a Package?</title>
      <para>
        Software for most versions of Linux is shipped as a
        <emphasis>package</emphasis> file, most commonly the 
        <systemitem>rpm</systemitem> or <systemitem>deb</systemitem>
        format. Each package contains a set of files that constitute
        the software itself, plus additional information about what
        the software is, what requirements it has, and where it should
        be installed.  Proper packaging makes software easier to
        install, upgrade, or remove, and can help manage the
        interdependencies among various programs.
      </para>
      <para>
        Ximian Red Carpet supports the <systemitem>rpm</systemitem>
        (Red Hat Package Manager, used by most distributions) and the
        <systemitem>deb</systemitem> (Debian) package formats.
      </para>

    </note>

    <para>
       <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application> also gives you
       access to two important services from Ximian, Inc.  The first
       service, Red Carpet Express, is for individuals, and offers
       access to special high-speed servers with faster connections,
       so you get better download rates.  The other service, Ximian
       CorporateConnect, is aimed at businesses and workgroups that
       want to manage software deployment on a relatively large scale.
    </para>
    <para>
      To find out more about using Red Carpet Express, read <xref
      linkend="rcx" />.  For more about Red Carpet Enterprise
      visit the <ulink
      url="http://ximian.com/products/red_carpet_enterprise">Ximian
      website</ulink>.
    </para>

    <note id="note-requirements">
      <title>Software Requirements</title>
      <para>
         <itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
            The <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application> update
            and installation services require a network
            connection. You can still use Ximian Red Carpet to remove
            software or install local packages without using a network
            connection. To install from a file, select
            <menuchoice> <guimenu>File</guimenu> <guimenuitem>Install
            Local Packages</guimenuitem>
          </menuchoice>. For information on removing software, see
          <xref linkend="rc-remove" />.
          </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para>
             To install, update, or remove software, you must enter
             your system's root password.  If you do not have root
             privileges, you may only view the software installed on
             your system.
          </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
     </para>
    </note>


    <para>
      A Red Carpet transaction works like this:
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select software you wish to install, update, or
            remove.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the <guibutton>Run</guibutton> button to start the
            transactions.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Ximian Red Carpet will check to make sure it is possible
            to perform the requested actions without installing or
            removing other programs.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            If necessary, Ximian Red Carpet will offer to add or
            remove additional software to satisfy requirements, giving
            you an opportunity to approve or cancel the actions.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            When you approve, click <guibutton>Continue</guibutton>
            and the actions will be performed.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>

    <para>
      To start using <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application>, select
      <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>System</guimenu><guimenuitem>Software
      Update</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the menu panel, or type
      <userinput>red-carpet</userinput> at the command line.
    </para>
  </sect1>


  <sect1 id="rc-channels">
    <title>Channels</title>
  <para>
    Ximian Red Carpet organizes software into channels, groups of
    software sorted by origin or topic.  "Red Hat 8.0," "Ximian
    Evolution Beta Snapshots," and "Ximian Desktop" are all channels.
    You can subscribe to different channels based on your interest in
    them. Software from channels to which you are not subscribed is
    not updated or installed.
  </para>

  <para>
    To subscribe to a channel, select    <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>Edit</guimenu><guimenuitem>Channel Subscriptions</guimenuitem>
    </menuchoice> or press the <guibutton>Channels</guibutton> button
    in the toolbar. A window will open to show you the list of
    available channels. Check the box next to a channel to subscribe.
  </para>

  </sect1>


  <sect1 id="rc-update">
    <title>Update</title>
  <para>
     When you start Ximian Red Carpet it will show you a list of
     software packages that you can update. An update notice is only
    shown for software that you already have installed, that is in a
    channel to which you are subscribed, and for which there is a
    newer version than what you already have. New software, and new
    versions of software that you have but that is in a channel to
    which you do not subscribe, is not part of the update screen.
  </para>

  <para>
    If you do not see any updates, make sure that you are subscribed
    to the right channels. See <xref linkend="rc-channels" /> to learn
    how to adjust channel subscriptions.
  </para>

  <para>
    To perform a simple update of your already installed software:

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Select all the items in your update list by clicking on them
          one by one or choosing <menuchoice> <guimenu>Edit</guimenu>
          <guimenuitem>Select All</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Mark the packages for installation by clicking the
          <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> button.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Click the <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button to have Ximian
          Red Carpet perform the updates.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </para>

  <para>
    You may also select individual packages for upgrade. 
  </para>


  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="rc-install">
    <title>Install</title>
    <para>
      To install new software,  click the <guibutton>FIXME</guibutton>
      button. This will <emphasis>not</emphasis> display a list of all
      available software, because that list would be far too long.  You
      must first search for the software you want to see. If you really
      wish to see every available piece of software, enter a blank search
      in the search box. It will take a while to display, however. 
    </para>
    <para>
      To search for software, select one or more criteria: type of
      software, channel, a few letters in the software's name or
      description, and so forth, and then press the
      <guibutton>Search</guibutton> button. Each package is 
      displayed with six columns of information:
     
      <variablelist>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Action</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The action you are performing for this package. This
              entry will be blank if you have not selected an action
              for the package. If you have selected an action, it will
              have an installation or removal icon. You can click on
              the blank space to perform an action (install a package
              if it is not installed, remove a packave if it is
              installed), or click on the icon to cancel the action.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Status</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The first column displays the package status. In addition to
              <guilabel>installed</guilabel> and <guilabel>not
              installed</guilabel>, package status may be
              <guilabel>older</guilabel>, meaning that the package
              displayed here is an older version than one you have
              installed or <guilabel>newer</guilabel>, meaning that
              the package here is newer than your version.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Channel</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The name of the channel in which this package is shipped.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Lock</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The column with the lock icon indicates whether the
              package is cryptographically signed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Package</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The name of the software package.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Version</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The version number of the package.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </para>

    <para>
      When you see an item you would like to install, click on it
      once to select it, then click the <guibutton>Mark For
    Installation</guibutton> button.  The package installation will be
    added to the list of transactions displayed on the left of the
    window.
    </para>
    <para>
      To remove an item from the list of pending transactions, select
      it and click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> or right-click on it and
      select <guimenuitem>Cancel</guimenuitem>.
    </para>

    <para>
      Proceed to choose other software you would like to install or
      remove. When you are done choosing software, click the
      <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button in the toolbar at the top
      of the window.
    </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="rc-remove">
    <title>Remove</title>
    <para>
      To remove software, click the <guibutton>FIXME</guibutton>
      button. This will display a list of all software installed on your
      system. You can narrow your list by selecting criteria from the
      search toolbar. 
    </para>
    <para>
      When you see an item you would like to remove, click on it
      once to select it, then click the <guibutton>Mark For
      Removal</guibutton> button.  The package removal will be added
      to the list of transactions displayed on the left of the window.
    </para>  
  
    <para>
      To remove an item from the list of pending transactions, select
      it and click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> or right-click on it and
      select <guimenuitem>Cancel</guimenuitem>.
    </para>

    <para>
      Proceed to choose other software you would like to install or
      remove. When you are done choosing software, click the
      <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button in the toolbar at the top
      of the window.
    </para>

  </sect1>


  <sect1 id="rcx">
    <title>Red Carpet Express</title>
    <para>
      Red Carpet Express is a high-speed, exclusive service that
      provides you with additional software. You should sign up for it
      today. FIXME: instructions go here.
    </para>

  </sect1>


</article>
