<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [

<!ENTITY rcversion "6.7.0">
<!ENTITY manversion "6.7.0">
<!ENTITY pubdate "August, 2005">

]>

<article id="index" lang="en">
 <articleinfo>
    <title>ZENworks Linux Management Update Client</title>
    <copyright>
      <year>2000-2005</year>
      <holder>Novell, Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
      <para>
      Novell, Inc. has intellectual property rights relating to
      technology embodied in the product that is described in this
      document. In particular, and without limitation, these
      intellectual property rights may include one or more of the
      U.S. patents listed at
      <ulink type="http" url="http://www.novell.com/company/legal/patents/"></ulink>
      and one or more additional patents or pending patent applications
      in the U.S. and in other countries.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>
      The <application>ZENworks Linux Management Update Client</application>
      formerly known as <application>Ximian Red Carpet</application>,
      is a program designed to help you manage the software you have on
      your computer. It can help you install, update, and remove programs,
      without making you keep track of dependencies and conflicts yourself.
      It works with the package management rules your operating system
      already has, so you can use it alongside unrelated command-line
      tools.
    </para>

    <note id="whats-a-package">
      <title>What is a Package?</title>
      <para>
        Software for most versions of Linux is shipped as a
        <emphasis>package</emphasis> file. Each
        package contains a set of files that constitute
        the software itself, plus additional information about what
        the software is, what requirements it has, and where it should
        be installed.  Proper packaging makes software easier to
        install, upgrade, or remove, and can help manage the
        interdependencies among various programs.
      </para>
      <para>
        ZENworks Linux Management supports only the <systemitem>RPM</systemitem>
        (Red Hat Package Manager) package format, which is used by most distributions.
      </para>
    </note>


    <note id="whats-a-channel">
      <title>What are Catalogs?</title>
      <para>
        ZENworks Linux Management groups software into catalogs.
        You can subscribe to
        catalogs that interest you, and ignore those that do
        not.
      </para>

      <para>
        To subscribe to a catalog, select    <menuchoice>
        <guimenu>Edit</guimenu><guimenuitem>Catalog Subscriptions</guimenuitem>
        </menuchoice> or click the <guibutton>Catalogs</guibutton> button
        on the toolbar. A window will open to show you the list of
        available catalogs. Check the box next to a catalog to subscribe.
      </para>
      
      <para>
        You can also mount a directory as a catalog, adding all packages within 
        the directory to the catalog. Click <guimenu>File</guimenu>, then click 
        <guimenu>Mount Directory</guimenu>. Specify
        the catalog name and browse to the directory that you want to mount as a
        catalog. Select the Look for Packages Recursively option to search the selected
        directory's subdirectories.
      </para>
    </note>

    
    <note id="note-requirements">
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <para>
         <itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
              A network connection is required for the ZENworks Linux Management
              Update Client to connect to a ZENworks Server and to gain access 
              to the catalogs and packages it provides. Without a connection, 
              the client can still perform installs, updates, and removals of 
              packages on the local machine. To install from a file, click
              <menuchoice> <guimenu>File</guimenu> <guimenuitem>Install
              from File</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice>. For information on removing software, see
          <xref linkend="rc-my-computer" />.
          </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para>
             To install, update, or remove software, you must enter
             your system's root password.  If you do not have root
             privileges, you may only view the software installed on
             your system.
          </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
     </note>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="getting-started">
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <para>
      To start using the <application>ZENworks Linux Management Update Client</application>,
      click <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>System</guimenu><guimenuitem>Software
      Update</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the menu panel, or type
      <userinput>red-carpet</userinput> at the command line. Enter
      your root password when prompted.
    </para>

    <para>
      The default view of the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client window 
      has two major sections that display
      information.  On the right side, there is a list of software
      packages.  On the left side of the window is a list of
      transactions.  As you use the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client, you will choose software
      from the package list to install or remove, adding the
      installation or removal to the list of actions.
     </para>
    
     <para>
      If you do not see any packages listed under any of the tabs,
      you may need to activate services. For more information, see
      <xref linkend="services" />.
     </para>
    
      <para>
        For detailed information about a package, select it and click
        the <guibutton>Information</guibutton> button.
      </para>

      <tip id="sort-order">
        <title>Sort Order</title>
        <para>
          To change the way information is sorted, click the headers
          at the top of the columns of data. For example, to sort
          software in alphabetical order by package name, click
          the <guilabel>Package</guilabel> header. Click again to sort
          in reverse alphabetical order.
        </para>
      </tip>

     <para>
       To select a package, click it with the left mouse button. You
       can select multiple packages by holding down
       <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> and clicking, or select a range using
       <keycap>Shift</keycap>. To select all packages in the list,
       press <keycombo><keycap>Ctrl</keycap><keycap>A</keycap></keycombo>.
     </para>

    <para>
      To mark a package for installation or removal, click the
      <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> or <guibutton>Mark
      for Removal</guibutton> buttons at the bottom of the screen. You
      can also click the <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column to choose
      an action for each package.
    </para>

    <note id="transaction-types">
      <title>How Many Kinds of Transactions Are There?</title>
      <para>
        There are two transactions you can perform using the
        ZENworks Linux Management Update Client:
        installation and removal. An upgrade is essentially
        the removal of the package's old version and installation of the new
        one. Therefore, there are only two actions you can choose:
        <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> and <guibutton>Mark for
        Removal.</guibutton>
      </para>
      <para>
        Where appropriate, the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client
        displays upgrades as though
        they were single transactions. For example, the
        <guilabel>Installed Software</guilabel> view has an
        <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column that displays upgrades as
        well as installs or removals.
      </para>
    </note>

    <para>
      To remove an item from the list of pending transactions, select
      it and click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> or right-click it and
      click <guimenuitem>Cancel</guimenuitem>.
    </para>

    <para>
      When you are done choosing actions, click the <guibutton>Run
      Now</guibutton> button. The ZENworks Linux Management Update Client
      will then check to see if
      additional actions are required. For example, if you attempt to
      install a new spelling dictionary, but you do not have the spelling
      tool, you will need to install the spelling tool as well as
      the dictionary.
    </para>
    <para>
       The ZENworks Linux Management Update Client will present you with
       a list of the actions that it
       is about to take, and ask you to confirm or cancel. If you are
       satisfied with the set of actions, click
       <guibutton>Continue</guibutton>.
    </para>
    <tip id="tip-mirrors">
      <title>Use a Mirror for Faster Downloads</title>
      <para>
        For best performance, select a mirror near you. To learn how
        to choose a mirror, and why mirrors can give you a faster
        download, read <xref linkend="prefs-general" />.
      </para>
    </tip>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="five-views">
    <title>Seven Ways of Looking at Software</title>

    <para>
      Along the top of the right side of the window are seven tabs that
      give you different views of your system:
    </para>
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Updates</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This is the view you will see when you start the
              ZENworks Linux Management Update Client.
              The Updates view displays updates to software that you have
              installed and that is in catalogs to which you are subscribed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Installed Software</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This view displays software that is installed on your
              computer.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
	   <term>Available Software</term>
	   <listitem>
	     <para>
	       This view displays software that is available to be installed on your
	       computer.
	      </para>
	   </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Search</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This view lets you search the largest possible list of
              packages: those installed on your system, and those
              available for installation in all catalogs.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
	   <term>Bundles</term>
	   <listitem>
	     <para>
	       This view displays Bundles that are installed on your
	       computer.
	      </para>
	   </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>History</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This view displays a list of actions you have performed in
              the past.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
          <term>Pending Actions</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              This view displays a detailed list of upcoming software
              transactions you have chosen. To perform them, click the
              <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button in the upper left
              hand corner of the window.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      
     <tip id="refresh">
     <title>Refresh</title>
      <para>
        Click the <guibutton>Refresh</guibutton> button to cause the 
        ZENworks Linux Management Update Client to communicate with the 
        ZENworks Server and get the lists of catalogs, packages, etc., that 
        the device has access to.
      </para>
     </tip>

      <sect2 id="rc-update">
        <title>Perform Updates</title>
        <para>
          When you start the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client it will show you a list of
          software packages that you can update. An update notice is only
          shown for software that you already have installed, that is in a
          catalog to which you are subscribed, and for which there is a
          newer version than what you already have. New software, and new
          versions of software that you have but that is in a catalog to
          which you do not subscribe, is not part of the update screen.
        </para>

        <para>
          If you do not see any updates, make sure that you are subscribed
          to the right catalogs.
        </para>


      <para>
        Each package is displayed with the following information:
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing for this package. This
                entry will be blank if you are neither installing nor
                removing it.  If you have selected an action, it will
                have an installation or removal icon. You can click
                the blank space to perform an action (install a package
                if it is not installed, remove a package if it is
                installed), or click the icon to cancel the action.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Importance</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The ZENworks Linux Management Update Client
                will indicate how important it is for you to
                install this update. From least to most important,
                an update can be listed as minor, feature, suggested,
                urgent, or necessary.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Catalog</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the catalog in which this package is
                shipped.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>New Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number for the updated package. Note that
                version numbers do not count by digits, but instead
                use numbers separated by a period (.). In other words, version 1.10
                is newer than version 1.9. You can remember this by
                referring to "one point ten" instead of "one point one
                zero."
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the software you have installed now.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
         </para>

        <para>
          To perform a simple update of software that is already on your system:
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select one or more packages in the list of available updates.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Mark the selected packages for installation by clicking the
                <guibutton>Mark for Installation</guibutton> button.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click the <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button to have the
                ZENworks Linux Management Update Client perform the updates.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </para>
        
        <tip id="update-all">
	      <title>Update All</title>
	      <para>
	        You can also click the <guibutton>Update All</guibutton> button to select
	        and update all pending updates.
	      </para>
    </tip>
    </sect2>


      <sect2 id="rc-my-computer">
        <title>Remove Software on My Computer</title>
        <para>
          To uninstall software that is on your computer now, click
          the <guilabel>Installed Software</guilabel> tab. The ZENworks Linux
          Management Update Client will
          display a list of the software that is on your system now.
        </para>
        <para>
          Select packages for removal and click <guibutton>Mark for
        Removal</guibutton> or click the space next to the package in
        the <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column. When you are finished,
        click the <guibutton>Run Now</guibutton> button, or select
        another view to choose more transactions.
        </para>

        <para>
          Each package is displayed with the following information:
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing on this package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Catalog</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the catalog in which this package is
                shipped.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
               The name of the package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the software you have installed now.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>
          There are three ways to change the items in the list:
        </para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Catalog</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Choose from the list of catalogs to show only the software
                that comes from a particular catalog.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Section</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Choose from the list of software sections to show only the
                software of that type. Some catalogs do not use section
                divisions.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Text Search</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                You can also search for a word or word fragment in the
                packages and their descriptions by typing into the text
                box above the list of packages.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <para>
          For this view and for the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> view, you
          will have the following additional search options:
        </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Search Package Descriptions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Check this box to search in package descriptions
                as well as package names.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>


          <varlistentry>
            <term>Any Words or All Words</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select <guilabel>Any Word</guilabel> for a broad
                search that matches any of the words you enter in
              the text box, or <guilabel>All Words</guilabel> to
              find only matches that contain all the words you enter.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Substrings or Whole Words</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Select <guilabel>Substrings</guilabel> to search
              for word fragments, or <guilabel>Whole
              Words</guilabel> to search for whole words
              only. Package names are rarely whole words, so this
              is mostly useful for package descriptions.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>
      <sect2 id="rc-search">
          <title>Search for Software</title>
          <para>
            To look at the broadest possible range of software, and to
            find new software to install, click the <guibutton>Search</guibutton>
            tab. This will <emphasis>not</emphasis> immediately display a list of all
            available software.  You must first search for the software
            you want to see. If you really want to see every available
            piece of software, enter a blank search in the search
            box.
          </para>

          <para>
            To search for software, select one or more criteria for your
            search. You can choose:
          </para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Catalog</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Narrow your search to a specific catalog. If you do not
                  select anything, you will search in all catalogs to
                  which you are subscribed.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>Section</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  The type of software you are looking for, such as
                  <guilabel>Productivity</guilabel> or
                  <guilabel>Imaging</guilabel>. The default is to search in
                  all sections.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>Status</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  You can search for packages that are not installed,
                  packages that are installed, packages that you have
                  installed but for which a newer version is available, or
                  for packages of any status. The default is to search for
                  all packages.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>Text Search</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Type words or word fragments to search for, and then
                  press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      <para>
        The advanced search options are the same as in <guilabel>My
        Computer</guilabel>. See <xref linkend="rc-my-computer" /> for
        more information.
      </para>


      <para>
        In the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> view, each package is
        displayed with the following information:
    </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The action you are performing on this package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Status</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Indicates whether you have the software installed and
                if so, whether an update is available. If you do not
                have the software, the value is listed as <guilabel>not
                installed</guilabel>.  If you have the same version of
              the software as the one listed, the status will be
                <guilabel>installed</guilabel>. If you have a
                different version, the listed package will be
                described as <guilabel>older</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>newer</guilabel> than the installed version.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Catalog</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the catalog in which this package is
                shipped.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lock Icon</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The column with the lock icon indicates whether the
                package is cryptographically signed.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the software package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The version number of the package.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>
    <sect2 id="rc-history">
      <title>View Past Transactions with History</title>
      <para>
        The history view displays a list of your past
        transactions. That is, each time you install, remove, or
        upgrade a piece of software, it's recorded here.
      </para>

      <para>
        The history information is taken from the logs of the Red
        Carpet Daemon, <command>rcd</command>. It includes
        transactions made with the <command>rug</command> command line
      tool, but not changes made with <command>dpkg</command>,
        <command>apt-get</command>, or <command>rpm</command>.
      </para>

      <para>
        It displays the following information about each transaction:
      </para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Time</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The time and date when the transaction occurred.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Action</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Whether you upgraded, installed, or removed the software.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>


          <varlistentry>
            <term>User</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The user who performed the action. In most cases, this
                will be <guilabel>root</guilabel>, but you may allow
                other users to use the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Package</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                The name of the software package involved in the transaction.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Old Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                For upgrades and removals, this is the version of the
                software you had installed before the transaction. For
                installs, this entry is blank.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>New Version</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                For Installs and Upgrades, this displays the version of the software after the transactions.
                For removals, this entry is blank.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      <para>
        To change the displayed list, you can choose one or more of
        the following criteria:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Transaction Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Normally, the <guilabel>History</guilabel> view shows
                you all transactions. You may choose instead to display just
                installations,  removals, or  upgrades.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>User</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Normally, the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client will show you transactions
                performed by all permitted users. If you have allowed
                other users to use the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client, you may choose to
                display just their actions. If you have not allowed
                any other users to change the system, the only option
                here will be <guilabel>All</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date Range</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Normally, the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client will show you the transactions in the last
                thirty days. You can choose a longer or shorter time frame if you wish..
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rc-transaction-view">
      <title>The Detailed Transaction View</title>
      <para>
        The left side of the main ZENworks Linux Management Update Client window shows you
        a list of transactions you have selected, but it doesn't have
        room to give you a lot of detail. For more information about
        your pending transaction list, click the
        <guibutton>Pending Actions</guibutton> tab.
      </para>
      <para>
        In addition to the action and package name available in the
        concise view, the detailed transaction view lets you see 
        the package version number and the amount of disk space taken
        up by the package.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

 
  <sect1 id="preferences">
    <title>ZENworks Linux Management Update Client Preferences</title>
    <para>
      To open the preferences window, click <menuchoice>
      <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> <guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
      </menuchoice>. The window has four tabbed pages: General, Cache,
      Daemon, and Advanced.
    </para>
    <sect2 id="prefs-general">
      <title>General Preferences</title>
      <para>
         You can set the following preferences here:
         <variablelist>
           <varlistentry>
             <term>Interval to Refresh Catalog Data</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                 Specify how often you want to refresh catalog data. The
                 default is two hours. 
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
               <term>Require Package Signatures</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   ZENworks Linux Management ships software with a cryptographic
                   signature. Unless you absolutely trust your server,
                   you should leave this setting on for increased security.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Maximum Number of Packages to Download at Once</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If possible, the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client will download
                   several packages at once in order to make the best
                   use of your network connection. If you have a very
                   fast connection, you can increase this
                   number. If you are sharing your connection with
                   others, you can reduce it.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	       <term>Enable Package Rollback</term>
	        <listitem>
	         <para>
	           Select this option to allow for packages to be rolled back.
	           When you upgrade or remove software, the ZENworks Linux Management
	           Update Client normally deletes the earlier version of the packages. If 
	           you select this option, earlier versions of packages are not deleted, and
	           you can roll back the software contained in them.
	          </para>
	          </listitem>
             </varlistentry>


             <varlistentry>
               <term>Use a Proxy</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If your network uses an HTTP proxy, check this box,
                   then specify the proxy URL. If necessary, also specify
                   your username and password. Because the ZENworks Linux
                   Management Update Client does not depend on a particular desktop,
                   this setting must be entered independently of
                   the GNOME desktop proxy setting.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
           </variablelist>
         </para>
       </sect2>
       <sect2 id="rc-prefs-cache">
         <title>Cache Preferences</title>
         <para>
           The ZENworks Linux Management Update Client stores downloaded files so that if you
           quit or cancel an operation, you can resume it quickly
           without downloading again. The <guilabel>Cache</guilabel>
           tab in the Preferences window lets you change cache handling
           behavior. Your options are:
           <variablelist>
             <varlistentry>
               <term>Cache Downloaded Packages and Metadata</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   If you don't want to cache anything, uncheck this box. It is normally on.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	       <term>Location of Cached Data</term>
	        <listitem>
	        <para>
	          Specify the location where you will save cached files. 
	          By default, this is /var/opt/novell
	          /zenworks/cache/zmd/web.
	                      </para>
	                    </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
               <term>Expiration</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Check the Cache Expires box to specify that the cache is emptied
                   according to the settings you configure. This option is set by default.
                   You can specify that the cache empties after a certain number
                   of days or if its contents take up more than a certain amount of
                   space. By default, this happens after 30 days or after the cache size reaches
                   300 MB. If you turn off cache expiration, packages
                   will be kept until you delete them yourself by
                   clicking the <guibutton>Empty Cache</guibutton> button.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
           </variablelist>
         </para>
         <para>
           At the bottom of the window, you can empty the package
           cache by clicking the <guibutton>Empty Cache</guibutton>
           button.
         </para>
         </sect2>
         <sect2 id="rc-prefs-advanced">
           <title>Advanced Preferences</title>
           <para>
             To change the preferences on the Advanced page, select the check box or click the Setting in the Value column, then 
             type the new setting. The options available in this section are:
           </para>
           <variablelist>

             <varlistentry>
               <term>Port to Listen On for Remote Clients</term>
               <listitem>
                 <para>
                   Specify the port to listen on for remote clients. The default is 2544.
                 </para>
               </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>Allow Clients to Connect Remotely to this Daemon</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        This setting is enabled by default.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>The Number of Milliseconds to Delay Before Retrying a Download</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 2000 milliseconds.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>Debug Level (Off, Min, Max)</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is Min.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>How Long Before Sending Delayed Actions, in Seconds</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 900 seconds.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>Number of Seconds until HTTP Requests Timeout</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 1800 seconds.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>Time of Day to Refresh Inventory</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 00.00:00 (midnight).
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>How Long to Wait between Retries of a Service Addition, in Seconds</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 300 seconds.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	       <term>Whether of Not Verified SSL Certificates are Required</term>
	       <listitem>
	        <para>
	         This setting demands that the ZENworks Linux Management Server
		 have an identity certificate that is verified by
		 external authority organizations. An external
		 certificate is expensive and most servers will not
                 have one. The default setting for this option is enabled.
	        </para>
	       </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>The Maximum Number of Download Retries</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is 3.
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             
             <varlistentry>
	      <term>IP Address to Bind To</term>
	      <listitem>
	       <para>
	        The default setting is empty, which means "all."
	       </para>
	      </listitem>
             </varlistentry>

                       
           </variablelist>

             <para>
               If you require finer control over the operation
               of the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client, you may want to edit the
               configuration files, as described in the man pages for
               <command>rug</command>, <command>rcd</command>, and
               <command>rcd.conf</command>.
             </para>
           </sect2>
         </sect1>

  <sect1 id="remote">
    <title>Using the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client with Remote Systems</title>
    <para>
      The ZENworks Linux Management Update Client
      may be used with remote systems running the
      Red Carpet Daemon, <command>rcd</command>.  You will need to
      have an account with the daemon on the remote system.
    </para>
    <para>
      To add an rcd account on the remote system, you must log in to that
      system as root, and use the <command>rug user-add -U username -P
      password</command> command. Then, you may administer the system
    without logging in as root.
    </para>
    <para>
      To connect to a remote system, do the following:
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Connect to Daemon</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click <guibutton>Connect to a Remote System</guibutton>.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the remote server.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Enter your user name and password.
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            Click the <guibutton>Connect</guibutton> button.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
      Once you are connected you can view and administer the system as
      you would a local one, in accordance with the privileges granted
      to your account.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can also use the <command>rug</command> command to administer
      a remote system. For information on the command line Red Carpet
      tools, use the <command>man rug</command> command.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="services">
      <title>Adding and Activating Services</title>
      <para>
        Using the ZENworks Linux Management Update Client, you can use 
        multiple servers for a single client. Each server is called a
        service.
      </para>
      <para>
        To add a service, do the following:
        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Click <menuchoice><guimenu>Edit</guimenu><guimenuitem>Services</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
  
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Click <guibutton>Add Service</guibutton>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
  
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Type the service URL, select the service type from the drop-down list, then
              type the registration key (optional).
            </para>
          </listitem>
  
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Click OK to add the service.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
          
       <para>
        To activate a service, do the following:
        <orderedlist>  
          <listitem>
	   <para>
	     Click <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Activate</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
	   </para>
          </listitem>
          
          <listitem>
	   <para>
	     Select the service from the drop-down list, type an e-mail address (or ensure that 
	     it is correct), then enter an activation code (optional).
	   </para>
          </listitem>
          
          <listitem>
	   <para>
	    Click Activate.
	   </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
   </sect1>

</article>